How do you feel about
Как ты относишься к
Stalin? Well, probably, if it’s not him and not the
Сталину Ну наверное если не он и не
Russian
русский
people, then Well, you know, I really don’t have
народ то Ну знаешь у меня прям нет
that kind of thing, like I somehow despise him. Well,
такого то что типа я его как-то презираю
if it weren’t for him, then what?
Ну если бы не он то
Hello about Ukraine I’m from the city of
что Здравствуйте о Украине Я из города
Khmelnitsk
Хмельницке
Hello, which of Khmelnitsky are you
Здравствуйте какого из Хмельницкий Вы
where are you from Tatarstan Kazan and what do you
откуда с Татарстана Казань а чём
communicate
общаетесь
here? Yes on everything Well, for example, did you have
тут Да на всяком Ну например а у вас
this Yesterday you didn’t have a holiday on May 9
этот Вчера праздник был у вас нет 9 Мая
Well, on May 9, yes, like we went and
Ну 9 мая да типа мы ходили цветы
laid flowers at the eternal flame And you went Yes,
возлагали к вечному огню А вы ходили Да
I just, I just saw that they canceled it for you
я просто я просто видел что у вас
this Immortal Regiment
отменили этот Бессмертный полка
action Well, I don’t know that
акцию Ну не знаю что
they went, well, with banners with
ходили ну с транспарантами с
photographs of grandfathers, they forbade
фотографиями дедов запретили ходить
walking on the streets No, they didn’t ban
Получается по улицах Нет не запретили А
Why didn’t they go, well, it’s because of
почему не ходили ну это потому что
security And what kind of security do
безопасность А какая безопасность у вас
you have in Tatarstan, what what kind of
у вас в Татарстане что что какая
security, that you can’t walk with
безопасность что нельзя походить с
grandfathers  drones
дедами беспилотники
are flying in right every day drones are flying in. Are
прилетают прямо каждый день прилетают
you kidding me, not
беспилотники Вы что прикалываетесь не не
drones, but a terrorist attack, not a
беспилотники а теракт не
terrorist attack, our grandfathers, our grandfathers, were not afraid of the Germans
теракт деды деды наши не боялись немцев
with a rifle, the German cops were not afraid, they fled, they were not
с винтовкой на немецкие копы бежали не
afraid of Mister
боялись Мистер
Shmitovsky somehow celebrated Look,
шмитовского как-то праздновали Смотри
whoever has it Who has the time,
Вот у кого есть У кого есть время да там
go there  to rallies at the Immortal Regiment, that’s
ходи там на митинги на Бессмертный полк
their business. So, let’s say, yes, well, and even you
это их дело Вот я допустим да ну и даже
know, there were fireworks, fireworks and
знаешь вот был там фейерверк салют ещё
something else. Yes, there was a parade, I didn’t
что-то Да там парад я туда не
go there, I quietly calmly went to the
ходил я тихо спокойненько сходил на
cemetery to visit my grandparents, we
кладбище к бабушке с дедушкой мы там
cleaned up there. That is, it turns out right.
убрались То есть получается правильно
you’re ashamed to show that you
вот вам стыдно показать что вы
support your grandfathers, so it turns out
поддерживаете своих дедов так получается
you don’t want to go to the parade Why do
вы не хотите выйти на парад Почему у нас
people come out with us But you don’t, and why not No,
Люди выходят А у вас нет да причём Нет
you’re talking at all You know now you’re
ты говоришь вообще Ты сейчас знаешь
turning it over, you
переворачиваешь
know, from head to toe You’re
вот знаешь с ног на с ног до головы Ты
just turning it over Well, look at me  was
просто переворачиваешь Ну смотри я был
ma I, what year were you born? Am I born in
ма я Ты какого года рождения Я
1981? Well, I’m younger than you, here I am. I
первого Ну я младше тебя вот я При
remember living in the Soviet Union for 10 years.
Советском Союзе помню вот 10 лет ещё жил
My grandfather was a war veteran. Every May 9th,
Мой дед ветеран войны он каждое 9 мая
he took me and we went to the parade. Honestly, I’m
меня брал и мы шли на парад Да чест с я
telling you again what  for
тебе ещё раз говорю то что в целях
security reasons, they canceled
безопасности Вот это всё отменили
all the crowds of people, they laid flowers on
скопление людей цветы возлагали все на
all the
всех
monuments, that is, parades were also held.
памятниках то есть также проводились
Why there was no Immortal Regiment,
парады Почему не было Бессмертного полка
I can’t answer you, you
я тебе ответить не
know, it’s just
смогу понимаешь ну просто
strange, I don’t understand why there
странно я вот не понимаю почему во всех
was an Immortal Regiment in all countries, you know, I have
странах был Бессмертный пол знаешь я СБО
little faith in the SBO  the fact that you have something in Western
слабо верю то что у вас в Западной
Ukraine there, you know, it was all
Украине там что-то знаешь так было всё
free, free, they came out, I look,
свободно свободно вон выходили я смотри
I took my grandfather too,
я взял да тоже своего деда на палку нет
but he’s not standing here with me. Well, go, I’ll go
Так он же у меня не тут стоит Ну сходи я
in the car in the car in my car
же пож в машине в машине у меня в
in the trunk, I went there in a car
багажнике я же на машине ездил туда аце
and there were people walking there, in my
вот и шли нас было человек вот в моём
city there were about 200 people somewhere and they were walking
городе человек 200 было где-то и шли
normally, the police are accompanying them so that
нормально полиция сопровождает чтобы не
there are no riots, terrorist attacks are
было каких-то беспорядков терактов
accompanying them like every year. And what’s the
сопровождает как и каждый год И в чём
problem, but in Russia, well  in Poland
проблема а в России ну в Польше
they held the Immortal Regiment in Germany
проводили Бессмертный полк в Германии
they held it yes in Germany in German
проводили да в Германии в немецкой
Germany they held the Immortal Regiment in
Германии проводили Бессмертный полк в
Russia why they didn’t conduct it
России не проводят
Well in some cities there was an
почему Ну в каких-то городах было
Immortal Regiment And your grandfather
Бессмертный полк А у тебя дед
fought, yes And what year of birth did you have?
воевал да А какого года рождения у тебя
Grandfather will now tell you what year of
Дед сейчас тебе скажу какого года
birth
рождения
about the fourteenth or the fifteenth
де четырнадцатого то ли пятнадцатого
year, then And how young you are, something can’t
года то А как ты моло чтото не может
be, it’s probably just a great-grandfather,
быть это наверное разве что прадед ты
what year were you
какого года
born? Why is my father’s great-grandfather Father,
рождения Почему прадед моего отца Отец
born, ninety-six ninety, and
родился девяносто шестой девяносто да
what year was your father
твой отец какого года
born, seventy-first, seventy-
родился семьдесят первый семьдесят
first, but it turns out that grandfather  born in the
первый а получается а дед родился в
fourteenth, it turns out that my grandfather
четырнадцатом получается что дед отца
gave birth to my father at 50-something
породил в 50 с чем-то
years old Yes, I have a brother Oh, my brother is the
лет Да у меня брат Ой брат отец самый
youngest in the family, he is the ninth grandfather, 57
младший в семьи де он девятый деду 57
years old Yes, yes, my father is the youngest,
лет было Да да у меня отец самый младший
it’s cool there are nine children in the family
прикольно их девять детей в семье
Uh-huh, I got it  such a question, like
Угу понял вот а такой вопрос Типа твой
what fronts
дед на каких в фронтах
did your grandfather fight on? I won’t tell you that,
воевал я тебе это не скажу
but they were captured and he was in ’42 or
но они попали в плен и он в сорок втором
something, when there were such fierce
что ли году когда вот такие прямо
battles, I won’t say exactly where, but he ended up in a
бои не не скажу точно где но попал в
concentration camp,
концлагерь э
Dachau, if you know one in  in the forty-second
дахау если знаешь такой в сорок втором
year since he was in Dachau, Paul Dachau was on the
году как он в дахау пол дахау был на
territory In short, not the USSR
территории Короче не СССР
Well, I know they were driven there like
Ну я знаю их угнали туда как
many. I mean, you’re lying about something, there’s a
многих В смысле что-то ты привирает вот
site for the memory of the people. For example,
есть сайт память народа Я например
mine is the official archives of the
своего это официальные архивы именно
defense of the Russian Federation, digitized Soviet ones, so I’m
обороны РФ оцифрованные советские так я
my grandfather  found Everything is there The battle
своего деда нашёл Всё там есть Боевой
path is all there, every grandfather is every grandfather
путь всё там каждый дед есть каждый дед
I’ll look now, it’s impossible that
Я сейчас посмотрю не может быт чтоб
Soviet prisoners of war were taken to Dachau
советских пленных в дахау типа забирали
in the
в со ВМ
year 2010. It’s about some kind of joke. No,
году это про какой-то прикол Не ну он
maybe he was somewhere else, I’m just
может где-то ещё был я тебе просто
telling you the final story.  his stop from where he was
конечную говорю его остановку откуда его
released And in what year was he released,
освободили А в каком году его освободили
well, after the war, they were apparently released by the
ну после войны их вроде освободили
Americans,
американцы
yes What was the surname, first name and patronymic of my grandfather,
да Как фамилия имя и отчество деда были
if I’m now on the site,
вот если я сейчас на сайте
I won’t tell you my middle name
загу отчество я не
Well, I won’t tell you, Although
скажу Ну хоя я тебе не скажу Хотя
the surname is the name and the surname is the name
фамилия имя а фамилия имя
I  I’ll write that, that is, How come you don’t
я те напишу то есть А как ты так не
know yours? I have priests Pavel
знаешь своего вот у меня попы Павел
Vasilyevich, I remember my
Васильевич я ж помню отчество
grandfather’s patronymic. You’re at the grave. When you come there, it’s
деда Ты же на могилу Когда приходишь там
written on the grave and like this, let’s
на могиле написано а вот так
see, it probably wasn’t enough.
было посмотрим
So now we
Так сейчас мы
’ll find
найдём
the grandfather. Which one?  year And the fourteenth year of
деда А какого года А четырнадцатого года
birth There are so many of them here
рождения Вот тут бляха их
and where was he
столько А где он
born so that at least the Tatar Autonomous Soviet Socialist Republic
родился чтобы хоть Татарская АССР
turns out to be Zainsk No there is one there in the
получается Заинск Нет есть такой там
fourteenth year where is
четырнадцатый год где
this for us What will it give now now now
ж это нам Что даст сейчас сейчас сейчас
by so here
по так вот
is the fourteenth year Abdul is not
так есть четырнадцатого года Абдул не
Abdullah but
Абдулла а
Abdul is now
Абдул сейчас
ours before  according to the documents, the Tyulyachinsky
наш раньше же по документам тюлячинский
district near Urum Serma is not he is not the
район у урум Серма это не он не место
birthplace of the Tyulyachinsky district of Tatarstan
рождения тюлячинский район Татарстана
Urum Sharma
урум шарма Нет
No, well, come on, read it, and the
ну ну-ка давай почитай а место
burial place is Leningrad region,
захоронение Ленинградская область
Starorussky district, this is not him no, no, no, not,
старорусский район это не он нет не не
he is not, that’s how
не не он не он так
it ended
закончились эти
today.  May 10th is his birthday, maybe
сегодня 10 мая у него днюха может
give it to many, there is no date of birth,
подари у многих нету даты рождения
only the year
только год
is there, but the year is the fourteenth. It’s not exactly the
есть но четырнадцатого года Нет точно
year fourteenth, he or it’s so
четырнадцатого года он или это так
approximately, you know, he told you
приблизительно зна е тебе сказал
the fourteenth
четырнадцатого
fifteenth Well, I also talked to one
пятнадцатого Ну я вот тоже вчера с одним
guy yesterday, it turned out that he has a
мужиком общался оказалось что у него
fake grandfather, like what  he didn’t
фейковый дед типа что он не
fight
воевал
so now we’ll find it
так сейчас найдём
like this We look at it from you that there’s a
так Смотрим от это у тебя что там сзади
log hanging behind there or did you do it call it a
лаг висит или ты это сделал называе
real
реальный
flag
флаг
so it is Shai Akhmetov Abdulla Gali
так так есть Шай Ахметов Абдулла Гали
Akhmetovich it’s not him no water Well, tell me
ахметович это не он нет водо Ну ты скажи
where you were born what But here not everything is
где родился что А тут вот не все есть
Where  were born
Где родились
so so there is
так так есть
Tatar Tatar USSR Novo Pysmyanka
татарский Татарская СССР Ново письмянка
region This is also not him and not there I’m
области Это тоже не он да не там я же
telling you what I’m speaking in No well, you
тебе говорю я на каком Не ну ты же ты же
know where his
знаешь где у него
grave is yes And you say burial Yes
могила да А ты захоронение говоришь Да У
Some have where he was born Some have
некоторых есть где родился у некоторых
where he was born  so there is Abdullah who
Где родился так так есть Абдулла который
was born in the village of Tashly Kovali or Tashly
родился в деревне Ташлы Ковали или Ташлы
Kovali
Ковали
no what district
нет какой район
maybe Dubki Dubki district there was some kind of I
может Дубки Дубки район какой-то был я
don’t
не
know Zainsky
знаю заинский
where In short you see something I don’t know
где Короче что-то видишь не знаю
no he told little on May 9 a cut
нету мало рассказывал он 9 мая гранёный
glass
стакан
some kind of cartoon like me  For the first time I hear
какая-то мулька типа я Впервые слышу
that they were sent to Dachau before Soviet
чтобы в дахау отправляли до советских
prisoners And he definitely fought for the Soviet Union,
пленных А он точно за Советский Союз
yes Or maybe he was for Idel
воевал да Или он может был это за Идель
Ural no Soviet Union The Red Army is
Урал нет Советский Союз Красная Армия
serious Cool This is interesting at all
серьёзно Прикольно Это интересно вообще
Not Ada, his
не Аде его
conla in the concentration camp learned German
конла в концлагере выучил немецкий язык
and always spoke, well, he told
и всегда говорил ну там рассказывал нет
no no some little things that those who didn’t know the
нет какие-то малости то что кто не знал
German language died very quickly And how
немецкий язык очень быстро умирали А как
he learned from him there was some kind of textbook on the
он выучил у него учебник был какой-то по
German language Well no, when you
немецкому языку Ну нет когда жить
want to live And when you are there somehow
захочешь И когда ты находишься там както
yes he teaches but he was like in the officer
да учит но он был как в офицерском
corps  just Look, I know, I’ll
составе просто Смотри я знаю вя
just say this, this is his phrase The German didn’t
просто скажу это вот его фраза Немец не
repeat it
повторял два
twice That’s it And look, it seems to me Well,
раза Вот так вот А смотри мне кажется Ну
look how he survived in the concentration camp Yes, if
смотри как он выжил в концлагере Да если
he was there, he learned German
он там был он выучил немецкий выучить
Only policemen could learn German in the concentration camp
немецкий в концлагере могли только
Yes, I tell you  even if, of course, I’ll
полицаи я те Да я тебе даже если конечно
say approximately In what years he was
приблизительно скажу В каких годах его
just reinstated in all ranks, the
только восстановили во всех званиях
awards were returned, it’s not the Soviet Union anymore, even he
награды это уже не Советский Союз даже
was already in Russia, just
был это ему уже в России его только
think about it in short, that is, he was acquitted
короче прикинь то есть оправ дали он
already, he was already a long time ago How everything died
уже он уже давным-давно Как умер уже всё
in Russia already  Just think, they stopped him
и в России его только прикинь остановили
in all ranks and then he was It turns out that
во всех званиях и то он был Получается
he collaborated in the camp like he
эти то он сотрудничал в лагере типа он
guarded these captured Jews
охранял этих пленных евреев
Yes no Why Well, how then Look Well,
Да нет Зачем Ну как как тогда Смотри Ну
how is it if he learned German, that
как это если он выучил немецкий язык то
is, they gave him textbooks there Yes, he
есть ему там давали учебники Да ему он
communicated with him  with the Germans Yes, these are
общался с немцами Да этими
his overseer then Well, look And there
надсмотрщика его потом Ну смотри А туда
yes yes yes And look, let’s say you come to us
да да да А смотри допустим вот ты к нам
in Tatarstan Yes And so they throw you into a
в Татарстан приедешь Да И вот тебя в
Tatar village Yes, like it or not,
татарскую деревню закинуть Да хочешь не
in six months you will begin to
захочешь через полгода ты начнёшь
understand the Tatar language yes Well he Look,
понимать татарский язык да Ну он Смотри
he doesn’t  I was sitting in a cell with the Germans.
он же не с немцами в камере
Well, it’s clear, but I’m telling you again
сидел Ну понятно но я тебе ещё раз
where I learned the German language and
говорю откуда о немецкий язык выучил и
his phrase was, if you want to live, you’ll learn it, the
его фраза была захочешь жить выучишь
German didn’t repeat it twice, that is, and
немец два раза не повторял то есть А
Katka won’t understand you, just
Катька будешь не понимать тебя просто бы
spank you at what exact moments. How he
шлёпнуть в каких именно моментах Как он
learned it textbook
это выучил учебник
studies while sitting Sitting in a concentration camp You can
учебни сидя Сидя в концлагере Можно
only learn the words there xox of
выучить только слова там хох
Russia I'll tell you more Well,
Руси я тебе Ну больше наверно скажу Не
he's probably the only one In conla learn the
он наверное единственный В конла выучи
German language and people in general for the war Oh
немецкий язык и вообще люди за войну О
he's not the first not the
он не первый не
last she German studied German
последний ше немецки изучали немецкий
studied school I'll tell you more from me
изучали школу я тебе больше скажу у меня
Abika who lived in Tatarstan she
абика которая жила в Татарстане она
knew seven
знала сем
languages ​​Grandmother
языков Бабушка
grandmother and which seven languages ​​she knew
бабушка а какие семь языком она знала
Arabic Tatar
арабский татарский
Tatar even not inclusive This
татарский даже вроде не включительно Это
native language was like that Well, what seven
родной язык был так так Ну а какие семь
languages ​​did she know French probably would have
языков она знала француский наверно бы
known some languages ​​Well for example
ну какие-то языки знал Ну например
Well here  take some eight languages,
Ну вот возьми каких-нибудь восемь языков
and if I don’t know which languages ​​I knew,
и вот если я не знаю какие языки знал
they also told me, I understood, and
мне также они и рассказывали понял А она
what was her grandmother’s job?
кем работала бабушка
I’ll tell you more, there’s such a Bauman Street in Kazan,
Я тебе больше скажу есть в Казани такая
now it’s the center of Kazan, so there
Баумана сейчас это центр Казани так там
were shops there, they had
было магазинов у них
hell there,  then the races were dispossessed not
ада там что-то рас раскулачивали не
dispossessed in short like this to
раскулачивали короче вот
In short, look I
ко Короче смотри я
understand How do you feel about Stalin
Поня Как ты относишься к Сталину
Well, probably if it’s not him and not the Russian
Ну наверное если не он и не русский
people Well, you know, I don’t really have that kind of
народ Ну знаешь у меня прям нет такого
thing, like I somehow
то что типа я его как-то
despise him if it weren’t for him then
презираю если бы не он то
what Well  It’s not his system that’s so political
что Ну не его система такая политическая
and
и
tough, they probably wouldn’t have won the
жёсткость то наверно не выиграли бы
war in
войну в
cm politically, before the war he repressed
см политическо он до войны репрессировал
a huge number of
огромное количество
military people, also, in short,
военнослужащих людей также само короче
some of your relatives over there
твоих родственников каких-то там вон
were dispossessed of kulakism And so on
раскулачивали И так дальше
Yes, it
Да
hung What kind of idiots it’s
завис Какие не терпилы
just that they have this one in short  the Russian
просто что у них короче вот этот русский
world is doing to the
мир делает с
brain, they are doing everything there, dispossessing everything,
мозгом они всё всё там раскулачить всё
If not for Stalin, this is how
Если б не Сталин вот как работает
the zombification of the empire works, just a
зомбирование империи просто
tinny letter on the Telegram right now, the
жесть пись на й Telegram прям зараз ось
VN
ВН
axis apoc tse even more and more politely YouTube, taking
апок це дуже и дуже важливо YouTube заня
us through skarg or in your ban and even
нас через скарг ор в твый бан и дуже
more video is not  I show people constantly not
багато вдео не показую людям вчасно не
showing information about the stream. To that end, in order for
показуе информация про стрими Тому для
Mali to write an operational link
того щоб ми Мали оперативный звязок
right away, in the meantime, in OKM, there
пишиться прямо зараз а пок там в окм
is also the same Tsikava and Korisna information
вдео ще теж цикава и корисна информация
and we will call you trimati
и мы пон з вами тримати
postiyiy operational link,
постийний оперативный звязок
in addition, we will show you the process
незалежно в того чи покаже вам проце
YouTube Slava Ukra  writing
YouTube Слава Укра пись